The first statement we need to
make this proof go is that B2,
the operator B2,
applied to Q1, dominates Q1.
&gt;&gt; Right, which you just
proved a slide ago, right?
&gt;&gt; Right.
And what did we call that?
&gt;&gt; Value improvement.
&gt;&gt; Good.
Yeah, the fact that we're using the
greedy policy with respect to Q1, one
step of update with respect to that gets
us a possibly better value function.
&gt;&gt; Right.
&gt;&gt; Great, now the next statement says
that if we iterate this operator, so
B2 iterated K times, applied to Q1,
versus B2 iterated K+1 times applied to
Q1, the K plus 1 one dominates the K1.
So this is kind of step
of a proof by induction.
But what's the main justification here.
What lets you make the statement that
one additional application of B2
is going to dominate
the previous adaptation.
&gt;&gt; So I'm going to say that it's
the other thing that you said
because I only remember
two things that you said.
And so that would be monotonicity.
It's the monotonicity of B2.
&gt;&gt; Right.
But if you've used up all these,
the next two boxes are going to be hard.
But just to go through why this is
the case, what we've done is we've taken
this first equation and
applied B2 to both sides.
Just over and over and
over and over again.
But since one dominated the other, after
we applied B2 to it, it still dominates.
Right that was like two slides ago that
was the whole point of monotinicity.
And they look very similar.
Value improvement and monotinicity
look very similar to one another.
&gt;&gt; Exactly.
And they all ground back in domination.
&gt;&gt; Right,
everything comes down to domination.
&gt;&gt; Boom.
&gt;&gt; Nice very nice.
Okay cool.
All right so we got value improvement
although I guess that's more accurately
value non-deprovement or something.
[LAUGH] Just to be you know
mathematically technical here and
then we've got monotonicity.
&gt;&gt; I like how you became more
mathematically correct and
less grammatically create.
&gt;&gt; Well those things are trade offs,
they're fundamental trade offs.
Okay so we've got that.
So we got value improvement,
we got monotonicity of our
value improvement so to speak.
And so
that's actually what the third thing is.
It's basically.
The monotonicity of
our value improvement.
You just kind of kept saying if I
keep doing the second thing over and
over and over again,
it keeps getting better and better.
Therefore the very last one that I do,
has to be better than the very first, or
at least no worse than,
the very first one that I did.
So I guess that's, there's a math
term for this transitivity.
A greater than B greater C,
A greater than C.
&gt;&gt; Oh, that's right.
&gt;&gt; So transitive property of
monotonicity non-deprovement.
&gt;&gt; I wouldn't say that.
It's what we get each time
we iterate this B2 operator,
we are getting something that dominates
the previous value that we had,
which dominates the previous one,
which eventually grounds out
in this first statement Q1, so
if you just chain all
those together we get- For
each of the possible ks the number of
iterations that we could apply the B2
operator, we're just getting more and
more monotonistically improved.
&gt;&gt; Right.
So that's,
but just remind everyone that's
just if a is greater than b and
b is great than c,
we know that a is greater than c.
Right?
Transitivity.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, that's just using transitivity,
but we're it over and
over and over and over and over.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, but it doesn't matter.
A greater than B greater than C greater
than D greater than E greater than
F greater than G.
&gt;&gt; Got it.
&gt;&gt; Okay.
&gt;&gt; And
then the last statement says, okay,
well now that that's true we
know that Q2 dominates Q1.
&gt;&gt; Right, and that's because you
said way up there at the top
that Q2 was the fixed point
of the B2 operator and
the limit of K approaching
infinity Vk of Q1 is in fact V.
Fixed point.
&gt;&gt; Good.
So it's the definition of
Q2 as the fixed point,
and this sort of notion that we can
just keep repeating this operator and
we get to the fixed point eventually.
Does it matter that there's
Q1 plugged in here?
&gt;&gt; No.
It does not.
Because you defined it that way.
&gt;&gt; Not that we defined it.
Well, up to this point,
we came through Q1.
But ultimately,
the fact that we get to Q2,
doesn't matter that we started at Q1
because there's a unique fixed point.
So no matter what value function we
start at, if we keep applying these
operators over and over and
over again we're going to get to Q2.
&gt;&gt; No matter what.
&gt;&gt; And so we did.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, but we want to be
able to relate it to Q1 and
doing it this way allows us to
do that in four easy steps.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, four slightly easy steps,
one slide per step.
But yeah, that's exactly right.
So we related Q2 and Q1,
which is to say we've related two
adjacent steps of policy
iteration to one another.
Each time we do a step of policy
iteration we get no worse.
This doesn't tell us that we can't
reach some kind of local optimum.
&gt;&gt; Mmhm.
&gt;&gt; But it is telling us that we're
getting the worse as we apply this
series of operators.
&gt;&gt; That's nice.
I like that.
So this is a pretty straightforward
derivation of fixed proof through
transitivity of value
non-deprovement monotonicity.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, obviously.
&gt;&gt; I like proofs.
I like obvious proofs.
[LAUGH]
&gt;&gt; I like the word non-deprovement.
&gt;&gt; We'll have to use that.
That could be the name of our band.