Now we have all the pieces to put
together a proof of policy iteration.
And since you have all the pieces,
you should be able to do it yourself.
So here's what I'm doing.
Let's take one step of policy iteration,
that is we start with some policy pi 1.
And just for notation, we have Bellman
operator B1 associate with that policy,
and Q1 as the fixed
point of that operator.
And then Q2 is the next policy we get.
It's the greedy policy with
respect to Q1 that we had from
the previous iteration.
And just again for notation, B2 will be
the Bellman operator for that policy,
and Q2 its fixed point.
And ultimately, what we want to show
is that the Q function that we get for
the second policy dominates
the Q function that we get for
the first policy.
And so this is how we're going to do it.
Were going to have a series of steps.
And each of them has justification that
we've been talking about recently.
Just fill in the boxes.
&gt;&gt; Good, I think I understand what
you want and I think I can do it.
&gt;&gt; Yeah and we'll try to be a little bit
generous with what the names of these
justifications.
But I did give names of these steps
in some of the previous slides.
So I'm hoping that those words
should still be jumbling around.
&gt;&gt; Some of them anyway.