Hey Charles.
&gt;&gt; Hey Michael, how's it going?
&gt;&gt; It's not going too badly.
I'm kind of excited.
because what we're going to
do in this section,
is take the previous two sections and
kind of mash them up.
&gt;&gt; Oh, I like that.
I always liked mashed sections.
&gt;&gt; So, in particular, we're going to
use some of the ideas from convergence
to better understand value iteration,
linear programming, and
policy iteration,
three algorithms for solving MVPs.
So I decided we could call it
Advanced Algorithmic Analysis, or AAA.
&gt;&gt; Oh, I like that.
And I like that you have a scarlet A.
&gt;&gt; Yes.
&gt;&gt; That's a nice allusion.
&gt;&gt; That's another A.
&gt;&gt; Yes.